# LT CDR BHUVAN KUMAR KUSHAL, PMP®, CSM®

**Project Manager** 

9686222190

kushalbhuvan.25@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/bhuvankk

kushalbhuvan.co.in github.com/bhuvankk

A result-driven, collaborative leader with strong communication, analytical & management skills and a passion for producing optimized results. Seasoned professional with 02 years of IT work experience at Infosys ltd and 10 years at Indian Navy. Experienced in Operations, Project Management and IT services.

## **Work Experience**

## Project Manager | Data Analyst, Indian Navy

(2015 – Present)

- Senior Project Manager, Project Panorama Led a team of 20 personnel in designing and developing a multi-crore worth software for providing round the clock weather forecast and tactical aid to 125 Indian Naval Ships, Submarines and 09 Air Stations for operations.
- Led a team of Meteorologists to carry out Operational Data Analysis, satellite data processing in Python and handled runs of state-of-the-art Numerical Weather Prediction algorithms/ models for Naval operations.
- Developed and deployed SOPs and risk mitigation procedures/safety protocols for flooding at Port Blair International Airport (Naval Air Station, INS Utkrosh) by carrying out a detailed Analysis to ensure safety of aircrafts and assets.
- Conceptualized and led planning and execution of a 13.5cr facility upgradation project.
- Planned, designed and developed a web application for weather data dissemination and satellite data transmission.
- Planned and executed project worth Rs 9.2cr for setting up of IT-based Aerodrome Meteorological instrument hub for safe flying operations.

# IT Project Manager, Indian Navy

(2012 - 2015)

- Spearheaded the Network Monitoring Centre of Indian Navy, directed and led a technical team of 20 personnel to ensure seamless availability of Naval Wide Area Network and Naval Satellite communication network for all naval units including ships and establishments.
- Successfully executed the first real-time Telemedicine trials over GSAT-7 satellite network on-board Indian Naval aircraft carriers.
- Achieved simultaneous overnight upgradation of network devices and protocols across Navy and thereby reduced the downtime.
- Conceptualised and developed a web application in PHP and My SQL for centralized accounting and handling of signal communication of entire Western Naval Command with up to 500 users.
- Planned and executed project worth Rs 10cr for provision of seamless satellite network connectivity to Naval Ships at Sea and Harbor.

## Systems Engineer, Infosys

(2010 - 2012)

- Performed stabilisation and bug fixes for Finacle 10.2 x versions. Debugged live issues of application hosted on Unix server by simulating them locally and resolving issues in the code using C/C++, Java coding expertise.
- Extensively used SQL for data handling including data manipulation.

### **Education**

- Business Management Program, IIM, Trichy, Aug 2022 – Present
- MSc-CUSAT, 2015 2016
- BE- Computer Science NMAMIT, Nitte, 2006 - 2010
- PGP in Data Science and AI Oct 2021 - Mar 2023

## **Key Skills**

- Project Management
- Data Analysis
- Machine Learning
- Python
- Agile
- SQL
- Tableau
- Web Development

### Certifications

- Project Management Professional **PMP®**
- Certified Scrum Master CSM®
- AWS-Certified Cloud Practitioner
- Global certificate in Data Science and AI - INSAID
- SQL certification Hackerrank
- IBM Certified Database Associate -DB2 9 Fundamentals
- Numerical Weather Modelling and Post processing in Python – School of Naval Oceanology and Meteorology